Guide to the Philip M. Weightman Papers WAG.194
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Philip M. Weightman Papers
1944-1967
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Weightman, Phillip M., 1902-
WAG.194
9 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
Philip M. Weightman, a native of Vicksburg, MS, began his career as a labor organizer and political activist as a teenager in St. Louis. In 1930 he moved to Chicago, where he became an organizer and representative of packinghouse workers. In 1948 he went to work for the CIO’s Political Action Committee, based in Washington. The collection documents in detail Weightman’s work as national field representative for the CIO Political Action Committee and as a staff member and Assistant Director of AFL-CIO COPE, until 1967. Correspondence, reports, publicity materials and clipping files document his work in labor and civil rights, with particular emphasis on labor’s role in campaigns for voter registration among African-Americans. NOTE: This collection is stored offsite, and advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Philip M. Weightman Papers were given to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives in December 1980 by Mr. Weightman. Some of the material represents his personal papers, kept at home, and other files are from his union office.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. NOTE: This collection is stored offsite, and advance notice is required for use.
Historical/Biographical Note
Philip M. Weightman was born in Vicksburg, Mississippi, in Jone 13, 1902. His father was Philip Mitchell Weightman, a contractor and butcher; his mother was Sarah Watts of Port Gibson, MS. In Vicksburg he attended St. Mary's Catholic School, the Cherry Street Public School, and Mrs. Johnson's School (during the summer months). Later he attended Sumner High School, at night, in St. Louis, MO.
In the fall of 1917, at the age of fifteen, Weightman joined the Amalgamated Butcher Workmen in St. Louis. He and his family had moved there from Vicksburg via Memphis in 1916. A year later, at sixteen, he cut his teeth in politics by organizing a get-out-the-vote drive in the old Fifth Ward, when his father, a precinct captain was taken ill. In the following years Weightman rose through the ranks in the packing houses of St. Louis and Chicago to respected stature in the labor movement.
At a St. Louis Labor Day Parade organized by the Butcher Workmen in 1918, Weightman experienced his first unpleasant act of discrimination. After the parade the union has a celebration and served food. He was standing in line when someone told him had to "get on the other line." This union attitude hurt him deeply; he left the event vowing that he would never join another union.
Following his marriage to Eulalia Mays in 1920, he worked for several packing companies, and, after an involvement with the Al Smith presidential campaign, moved to Chicago in 1930. In 1937 he helped to organize Local 28 of the Packinghouse Workers, CIO, and became Chief Steward in his plant. In 1943 he became First International Vice-President of the United Packinghouse Workers, a post that he held until 1948 when he joined the staff of the CIO's Political Action Committee (PAC). CIO President Philip Murray selected Weightman for a special assignment in Panama to reorganize the administrative structure of the Government Employees Union there. He served as a Field Director for CIO-PAC from 1948 to 1955, and when the AFL and the CIO merged in 1955, he became a Field Director of the newly formed Committee on Political Education (COPE). In 1960 COPE Director James L. McDevitt named him Assistant National Director of COPE.
Weightman was also involved in community and civil rights activities. He was a member of the Chicago Human Rights Committee, First Vice-President of the Chicago NAACP, and a founder of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference; and he often served as a consultant for the National Urban League and other groups. He worked tirelessly to increase black voter registration in the North and South, and formed alliances with other minority groups, in particular Puerto-Rican Americans and other Latino communities. His efforts on behalf of voter registration contributed to some crucial electoral victories. He played an active role in the Congressional elections of 1954, convincing his colleagues to emphasize economic as well as civil rights issues.
Among his notable achievements were the defeat of right-to-work proposals in California and Ohio, a record turnout of black voters for Senator Kefauver in Tennessee in 1959; helping build the overwhelming minority vote for John F. Kennedy in 1960; and upset New Jersey election of Richard Hughes for governor in 1961.
Upon his mandatory retirement in 1967 he was hired by the Office of Economic Opportunity as a Supervisory Labor Relations Specialist. He served as principal contact for those with questions concerning interpretation and application of labor-management agreements, unfair labor practices complaints, third party involvement in the agency labor relations program, and other related matters. Weightman retired completely from government employment in 1980.
Scope and Content Note
The collection documents in detail Weightman's work as national field representative for the CIO Political Action Committee and as a staff member and Assistant Director of AFL-CIO COPE. There is no information on his early career and political activities or on his later move, after mandatory retirement from the AFL-CIO, to the Office of Economic Opportunity.
Series I: CIO-Political Action Committee, 1947-1958, consists of two sections, work files arranged alphabetically by state and subject files arranged alphabetically by personal name or topic. Included are reports, memos, publicity material, correspondence and newsletters.
Series II: AFL-CIO-Committee on Political Education, 1949-1962, begins with a series of files arranged alphabetically by state. Documenting the political work of AFL-CIO COPE, mostly for the period 1957-1962. The state files are followed by several groups of subject files, arranged alphabetically. Notable are the correspondence and reports of COPE Director Alexander (Al) Barkan and field workers Fannie Neal and Earl Davis (the latter reported to Weightman). Contents include incoming and outgoing correspondence, reports, publicity material, lists of volunteers, and background files on various political organizations. The last group of files documents political activity of AFL-CIO COPE at the national and international levels, including relations with the Democratic Party and interest in Mexican political developments.
Series III: General Correspondence, 1951-1967, is comprised of incoming and outgoing correspondence, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. These files give a detailed picture of Weightman's work as AFL-CIO COPE Assistant Director; notable are the extensive reports by Earl Davis on voter registration efforts in the South.
Series IV: Voter Registration, 1951-1967. This series thoroughly documents an issue that was a very high priority for AFL-CIO COPE in mid-century. Voter registration campaigns are tracked state by state and community by community, with background files on finances, cooperation with the NAACP and other organizations, statistical studies, training programs and conferences, and analyses of voting laws.
Series V: Working Files, 1956-1962, consists of subject files covering all aspects of Weightman's work, arranged alphabetically. The files are especially rich in material documenting the changing history and status of African-Americans in the period. There are files on racial integration in industry, education,, the armed forces and government; the civil rights movement and Martin Luther King, Jr.; African-American organizations and media; and voting patterns.
Series VI, Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1955-1967, covers many of the same topics found in the subject files of Series V, but with an additional special emphasis on Africa and African political leaders. The clippings are mostly from the New York Times, the Washington Post, and local newspapers in the South. Press releases are mostly from U.S. labor and political organizations.
NOTE: This collection is stored offsite, and advance notice is required for use.
Arrangement
Each series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
Organized into 6 series:
Missing Title
I, CIO-Political Action Committee, 1947-1958
II, AFL-CIO-Committee on Political Education, 1949-1962
III, General Correspondence, 1951-1967
IV, Voter Registration, 1951-1967
V, Working Files, 1945-1967
VI, Newspaper Clippings, 1955-1967
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Oral history interview with Philip M. Weightman, in New Yorkers at Work Collection (OH 1), Tape 133.
Separated Material
Photographs from the Philip M. Weightman collection have been transferred to the Non-Print Department of the Tamiment Library.
Guide to the Philip M. Weightman Photographs (Photographs 025)
Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Civil rights workers.; African American labor union members.; African Americans -- Civil rights.; Voter registration.; Speeches.; Reports.; African Americans |x Suffrage.; Newsletters.; Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (U.S.); National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.). Political Action Committee; AFL-CIO. Committee on Political Education; Davis, Earl Wayne; Barkan, Alexander E.; Neal, Fannie
- Series I: CIO Political Action Committee, 1947-1958.
  - Alabama-Congressional, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alabama-Local, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alabama-State, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arkansas-Congressional, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arkansas-Local, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arkansas-State, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arizona-State, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - California-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - California-Local, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - California-State, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Colorado-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut-State, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Delaware-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Florida-Congressional, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Florida-Local, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Florida-State, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Georgia-Glynn County Civic League, Dekalb, Fulton, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Georgia-Local, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Georgia-State, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Idaho-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Illinois-Chicago, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Illinois-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Illinois-Local, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Indiana-Congressional, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Indiana-Local, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Indiana-State, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Kansas-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Kansas-State, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Kentucky-State, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Louisiana-Local, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Louisiana-State, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Maryland-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Maryland-State, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Massachusetts-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Massachusetts-State, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Michigan-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Michigan-State, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Michigan-UAW-CIO, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Minnesota-Congressional, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Minnesota-State, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Mississippi-Local, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Mississippi-State, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Missouri-Congressional, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Missouri-Local, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Missouri-State, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Montana-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Nevada-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - New Hampshire-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - New Jersey-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - New Jersey-State, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - New York-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - New York-Local, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - New York-Negro Labor Committee, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - New York-State, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - North Carolina-Congressional, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - North Carolina-Local, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - North Carolina-State, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Ohio-Cleveland, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Ohio-Congressional, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Ohio-Local, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Ohio-Right-to-Work, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Ohio-State, 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Oregon-State, undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Pennsylvania-Congressional, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Pennsylvania-Local, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Pennsylvania-Philadelphia Campaign, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Pennsylvania-Philadelphia, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Pennsylvania-State, 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Rhode Island-Congressional, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - South Carolina-State, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Tennessee-Congressional, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Tennessee-State, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Tennessee-Memphis, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Texas-Congressional, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Texas-State, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Utah-Congressional, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Virginia-Congressional, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Virginia-Family Participation Conference CIO-PAC, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Virginia-Local, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Virginia-State, 1947-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Washington-Congressional, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - West Virginia-Congressional, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - West Virginia-Local, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wisconsin-Congressional, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Wisconsin-Local, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Wisconsin-State, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - American Labor Education Service, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Anti-Discrimination-CIO Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Burke, Tom, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Carey, James, Secretary -Treasurer, CIO, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Census, Bureau of US Statistics, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - CIO-Committee to Abolish Discrimination, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CIO-Convention Proceedings, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - CIO-Council Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - CIO-PAC, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - CIO-PAC, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - CIO-PAC, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - CIO-PAC, Data (Reports), 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CIO-PAC, Memoranda, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - CIO-PAC Reports, Weightman, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - CIO-PAC Research Department, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - CIO-PAC, Statistics, 1952-1952 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Civil Defense, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Civil Liberties, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Clark, John-Pittsburgh Courier, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Conference on Family Participation, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Dawson, W. L., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Democratic Party, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Dudley, Tilford E., 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Federal Security Agency, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Free Trade Union Committee, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Government Data, Philadelphia: Cost of Living Index, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Guernsey, George T., CIO-Education, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Haywood, Allan S., CIO Executive V.P., 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Housing List, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Jones, Brownie Lee, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Korea: General McArthur, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Kroll, Jack, Director, CIO-PAC, 1947-1956 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Mitchell, Clarence, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Murray, Henry F., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Murray, Philip, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - NAACP, National, 1948-1956 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - NAACP News, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - National Association of Colored Women, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - National Association of Colored Women: Ella P. Stewart, President, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - National Council for a Permanent FEPC, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Negro, 1950-1954 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Negro Newspapers, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Orders, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Oliver, Robert, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Packinghouse, 1948-1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Payne, Ethyl, Memoranda-PAC, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pearson, Drew, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Phil-Miscellaneous, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Political Action of the Week (PAW-CIO) Newsletter, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Presidential Election Report (Minority), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Printer’s Ink, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Public Schools, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Reed, Harry-CIO, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Republican Party, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Reuther, Roy: Political Action, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Riffe, John V., CIO V.P., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Smith, Darrel O., CIO-PAC Asst. to Jack Kroll, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - State Department: Employee Loyalty, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Statements: Negro, undated, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Truman, Harry S., President, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Turner, James-Rubber Workers, CIO, 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - UPWA-CIO, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Urban League, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Washington, DC, undated, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Weightman, Philip-Form Letter Copy, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Weightman, Philip-PAC Reports, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Women: List and Organizations, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Series II: AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education, 1949-1962.
  - Alabama-Congressional, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Alabama-Local, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Alabama-State, 1957-1962 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Arkansas-State, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - California-Local, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - California-State, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Florida-Local, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Georgia-Congressional, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Georgia-Local, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Illinois-Local, 1949-1961 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Illinois-State, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Indiana-Local, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Indiana-State, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Kansas-State, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Kentucky-State, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Louisiana-State, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Maryla-Local, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Maryland-State, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Massachusetts-Local, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Michigan-Congressional, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Michigan-State, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Minnesota-State, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Mississippi-Local, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Mississippi-State, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Missouri-Local, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - New Jersey-State, 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - New York-Local, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - New York-State, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Ohio-Congressional, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Ohio-Local, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Ohio-State, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Oklahoma-State, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Pennsylvania-Harrisburg, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Pennsylvania-Local, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - South Carolina-State, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Tennessee-State, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Texas-Congressional, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Texas-Local, undated, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Texas-Poll Tax, undated, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Texas-State, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Virginia-Local, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Virginia-State, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Washington-State, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Washington, DC-Miscellaneous, 1955-1962 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - West Virginia-Local, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - West Virginia-State, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Wisconsin-State, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Barkan, Alexander E., 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Bartkin, Walter, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Biemiller, Andrew J., 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Brown, Theodore, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Committee on Political Education-National, 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Dashiell, F.K., 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Davis, Earl W.-Correspondence and Memoranda, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Davis, Earl W.-Correspondence and Memoranda, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Davis, Earl W.-Reports, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Davis, Earl W.-Reports, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Davis, Earl W.-Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dial, John H. Jr., Los Angeles, CA, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dudley, Tilford E., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ellinger, W. Don, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Guernsey, George T., 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hawkins, John A., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hobby, Wilbur, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - McDevitt, James L., 1956-1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - McPeak, C.A., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Meany, George, 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Murray, Esther, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Murray, Henry F., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Neal, Fannie, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - O’Brien, Jack, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - O’Brien, John T., Machinist Nonpartisan Political League, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Oliver, William H., 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Payne, Ethel, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Randolph, Philip A., 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Reuther, Roy L., 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Riffe, John V., undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Thornton, John, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Woll, J. Albert, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Action Bulletin, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - AFL-CIO. Department of Education, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - COPE Registration, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - COPE Report, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Focus on the UN, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Kohler Strike, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Monthly Office Expense Report, 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Monthly Office Expense Reports, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Notes and Memoranda from COPE [and PAC], 1952-1962 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Organizations Participating in COPE Voluntary Contribution Drive, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Political Memoranda from COPE, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Transportation Vehicles Inc., 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - American Airlines, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Big Business, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Central Labor Union, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Civil Rights, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Democratic National Committee-Advisory Council, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Election Data, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Election Statistics and Reports, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Hill, Herbert, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Inauguration, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Indians, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - John Birch Society, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Matthew, Crockett and Ballard, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Mexico-Inauguration, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Moon, Henry Lee, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Mitchell, Clarence, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Negro Vote, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 55)